ghanaguardian.com 2019-09-03

# Privacy - The Ghana Guardian News

We at Ghana New Services, incorporating Ghanaguardian website, strongly believe in protecting the confidentiality and security of information we collect about individuals. The material below describes our privacy policy and describes how we treat the information we receive about you if you interact with any of our sites.

**Why We Need to Know About You**

We need to know about you so that we can provide you with information on products and services and better target our sports content offering to your interests. What we need to know about you includes your address, age and preferences.

**How We Learn About You**

What we know about you we get mostly from you. But we may also have to find out more about you from other sources in order to make sure that what we know about you is correct and complete. We do not collect personally identifiable information about you except when you specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis. For example, such personally identifiable information may be gathered from competitions, message boards, suggestions and transactional areas.

**Your Right To Opt Out**

At our points of data collection, you have the opportunity to indicate whether you would like to "opt in" or "opt out" of receiving promotional and/or marketing information about other products, services and offerings from group companies and/or third parties on whose behalf we may send out information. Further, notwithstanding any opt out of promotional information by the user, we reserve the right to contact you regarding account status, changes to our service agreement and other matters relevant to the underlying service and/or the information collected. You can request to "opt out" of further promotional contacts at any time and all promotional emails we send you allow you this facility. Also, upon request, we will use commercially reasonable efforts functionally to delete you and your personal information from our database; however, it may be impossible to delete a your entry without some residual information due to backups and records of deletions.

**How We Protect What We Know About You**

We treat what we know about you confidentially. Our employees take care in handling your information. They may get information about you only when there is a good reason to do so. We take steps to make our databases secure and to safeguard the information we have about you.

**How We Use and Disclose What We Know About You**

We may use anything we know about you to help us serve you better. We will not disclose your information to any third party save for the following exceptions:

* To help us process questions you may have about a purchase, registration or other inquiry you may have.

* To confirm or correct what we know about you.

* To help us or law enforcement agencies prevent fraud, money laundering, terrorism and other crimes.

* To allow for verification of what we know about you.

* Data processing requirements.

* Assisting an agency perform research for us.

* Compliance with the law or request of a government agency for example, complying with a search warrant.

* Compliance with an audit our business.

* If we sell all or any part of our business or merge with another company.

Generally, we will disclose only the information we consider reasonably necessary to disclose.

**How You Can See and Correct Your Information**

Generally, we will let you review what we know about you if you ask us in writing or email. If you tell us that what we know about you is incorrect, we will review it. If we agree with you, we will correct our records.

**Third Party Data Collection**

You should be aware that sites within the group might sometimes permit third parties to offer you subscription, registration-based services, promotions or competitions through our network. We are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties and users should check the applicable privacy policy of such party when providing personally identifiable information to other parties.

**Sharing Your Data in Public Areas of our Sites**

You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information (e.g. user name, e-mail address) on any of our message boards, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and correlated and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or third parties. Such activities are beyond our control.

**How We Use IP Addresses**

We may use your IP address to help diagnose any problems with our server or to administer our websites. Your IP address may be used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information that helps us understand user requirements. This specific information will only be used within our organisation and we will only share or use thisinformation on an aggregate basis.

**How We Use Cookies**

We collect non-personal information and data through the standard operation of our servers or through the use of cookies. Cookies are small text files a web site used to recognise repeat users, facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the site, track usage, follow site behaviour and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising. Cookies are not programs that come onto a your system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user that has no meaning outside the assigning site. Cookies can help you for example by delivering content specific to your interests, or to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site. Our sites employ the services of an outside companies to serve and appropriately target online advertisements and track site usage. To do this, their software collects anonymous data through the use of cookies. Users should be aware that we cannot control the use of cookies or the resulting information by advertisers or third parties hosting data for us. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the cookie feature; however, you should note that cookies may be necessary to provide the user with certain features (e.g. customised delivery of information) available on our web sites.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our site contains links to other sites outside of our control. We are not responsible for the content of those websites.

**Privacy Policy** -

Ghanaguardian.com knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By visiting our website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy covers Ghanaguardian.com 's treatment of personal information that Ghanaguardian.com gathers when you are on the Ghanaguardian.com website and when you use Ghanaguardian.com services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Ghanaguardian.com does not own or control, or to individuals that Ghanaguardian.com does not employ or manage.

**Information Collected by Ghanaguardian.com**

We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We do not process this information in a way that is incompatible with this objective. We collect the following types of information from our Ghanaguardian.com users:

1\. Information You Provide to Us: We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features.

2\. **Automatic Information** :

o We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. Ghanaguardian.com and its authorized agents automatically receive and record certain "traffic data" on their server logs from your browser including your IP address, Ghanaguardian.com cookie information, and the page you requested. Ghanaguardian.com uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website.

o Ghanaguardian.com may collect and, on any page, display the total counts that page has been viewed.

o Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously. While Ghanaguardian.com will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these programs are available.

**E-mail Communications**

Ghanaguardian.com is very concerned about your privacy and we will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the "Sharing Your Information" section below. Ghanaguardian.com may send out e-mails with Ghanaguardian.com -related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions.

**Cookies**

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Ghanaguardian.com cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or e-mail address is.

The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We recommend that you leave the cookies activated because cookies allow you to use some of Ghanaguardian.com 's coolest features.

Ghanaguardian.com 's advertising partners may place a cookie on your browser that makes it possible to collect anonymous non-personally identifiable information that ad delivery systems use to present more relevant ads. If you would prefer to opt-out of this standard practice, please visit our advertising partner Platform-A's privacy policy and opt-out page.

**Sharing Your Information**

Rest assured that we neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone and that we will share your personal information only as described below.

Ghanaguardian.com Personnel: Ghanaguardian.com personnel and authorized consultants and/or contractors may have access to user information if necessary in the normal course of Ghanaguardian.com business.

**Business Transfers:** In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Ghanaguardian.com, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred.

**Protection of Ghanaguardian.com and Others:** We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Ghanaguardian.com, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Syndication:** Ghanaguardian.com allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the Ghanaguardian.com website.

**With Your Consent:** Except as noted above, we will contact you when your personal information is shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to opt out to prevent the sharing of this information.

**Children Under 18 Years of Age**

You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Ghanaguardian.com website. As a result, Ghanaguardian.com does not specifically collect information about children. If we learn that Ghanaguardian.com has collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. We recommend that minors between the ages of 13 and 18 ask and receive their parents' permission before using Ghanaguardian.com or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Ghanaguardian.com may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Ghanaguardian.com website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed.

**Conditions of Use**

If you decide to visit Ghanaguardian.com website, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of California state law.

**Effective Date of this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of 8th September, 2008 and last updated 8th September, 2018.
